Eric Gausnell

gausnell@gmail.com | Seattle, WA | linkedin.com/in/eric-gausnell

SOFTWARE QA ENGINEER

QA Engineer with over 10 years' experience as a key member of core software development teams with expertise working to improve quality on a wide variety of projects spanning front and backend of mobile social media apps, e-commerce platforms, web applications and proprietary support tools. I have proven success designing and executing comprehensive test plans and automation development supporting features and enhancements throughout the product development lifecycle.

CORE SKILLS

- Functional, regression testing
- Automated test creation UI and API
- Test planning and design
- Problem-solving, unblocking
- Excellent written communication / collaboration
- Discover, triage and document defects
- Agile / SDLC Scrum/Kanban
- · Identify project design issues early
- Interpret requirements, acceptance criteria
- Aptitude and curiosity for learning

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Java, Selenium WebDriver, RestAssured, TestNG, Python, Pytest, Javascript, SQL, AWS, Docker, Git, Postman, Jira, WordPress

RECENT EXPERIENCE

TikTok (ByteDance) via Millennium Software / Deloitte QA Engineer | Project Delivery Specialist II

Oct 2022 - Dec 2024

- Recognized as TikTok All Star by Deloitte for demonstrating quick product knowledge ramp up across multiple domains.
- Acted as primary liaison between US and Non-US teams ensuring quality of new feature rollouts for e-commerce marketplace aftersales support and seller onboarding process.
- Lead QA on project to modularize third-party vendor integration platform in EU and US marketplaces. This
 led to the ability to more rapidly integrate all new primary and secondary vendors used to verify ID,
 addresses and provide risk assessments during the seller onboarding process.
- Provided testing and joint debugging support to offshore teams for e-commerce feature migrations and new features within US data center while maintaining strict US data privacy protocols.
- Created and maintained automated Python RPC, HTTP and event-driven API framework and test cases for testing various interfaces, queues and endpoints, decreasing time to iterate over existing features with high confidence in quality. Integrated test suites into CI/CD pipelines.
- Performed manual QA testing for major e-commerce initiative to integrate TikTok Shop into third-party platforms Salesforce, Shopify and Woo Commerce increasing customer efficiency and satisfaction.
- Configured and monitored automated flow-based API response diff testing integrated into CI/CD pipelines providing an extra layer of regression detection in services where automated coverage was sparse.
- Authored tool and process documentation; trained and mentored newly on-boarded team members.
- Developed dashboards for monitoring success/fail rate of nightly execution of automated test cases and tracking of Jira issues in team project via Jira API.

All Star Directories Oct 2012 – Jun 2022

Senior QA Engineer, Lead QA Engineer, QA Engineer

• I was primary QA in all stages of Agile SDLC from design to post-deployment while consistently delivering upon initiatives originating from various functional areas within the organization.

- Sustained high quality metrics over the evolution of the company's platform consisting of initiatives such as enabling new product offerings, conversion optimizations, compliance updates and iterative functional and design enhancements over a 10-year period.
- Developed and executed on comprehensive test plans for each assigned project. This included design of manual and automated testing strategies, conditions and cases, configuration of test environments and creation or obtainment of test data.
- Lead QA resource on 'Linkout' initiative, an Epic size project that enabled the business to realize new revenue sources. The project enabled surfacing of a new type of offering and the tracking of impressions, clicks and conversions from visits interacting with these offerings across domains.
- Built out new Selenium WebDriver/Java-based automation framework and converted existing manual regression test cases to automated tests for CI/CD integration in Jenkins then Gitlab Auto DevOps.
- Maintained and updated QA processes during platform migration from company-owned hardware to AWS.
- Created UI automation to fill, submit and validate dynamically generated complex multi-pane forms.
- Integrated existing automation with BrowserStack to facilitate testing across mobile device matrix.
- Lead QA resource on project to develop new public API for sharing of inventory with partners vastly improving the partner integration and onboarding process.
- Provided optimization suggestions and certification of new partners' integrations of newly developed API by working closely with partners' dev teams.
- Created automation test suite to test new API against DB data using custom developed SQL queries.
- Attended product story reviews providing input on requirements, designs, effort estimations and potential issues to get stories sprint ready.
- Supervised and delegated all QA activities throughout each sprint between QA team members.
- Subject Matter Expert on internal processes, product features and mentor of junior team members.
- Configured and ran SiteSpect A/B test campaigns, metrics and triggers for new features and optimizations.

All Star Directories | Production Engineer

Sept 2008 - Oct 2012

- Created and maintained code solutions developed in PHP and Java from customer technical requirements to format and post platform-hosted form data to customer APIs (CRM) in real time.
- All Star Directories began work to migrate from their legacy PHP platform to a new Java-based platform architected in-house in 2009. I was tapped to provide assistance in specification gathering and to rewrite and test 80+ PHP classes into their Java equivalents.

EDUCATION

Oracle Certified Java Associate ISTQB Certified Tester Foundation Level